Keys mss., 1972-1982 LMC 2716
Lilly Library
Keys mss.
1972-1982
Lilly Library
Keys, Donald
Aké, Simeon.
Biden, Joseph R.
Cranston, Alan, 1914-2000.
Roosevelt, Curtis, 1930-
LMC 2716
6 Boxes
The Keys mss., 1972-1982, consists of the papers and correspondence of writer Donald Keys, 1924-2008, pertaining to his work with the World Association of World Federalists.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2003
Biographical Note
Donald Keys, 1924-2008, was a writer and the World Association of World Federalists' representative to the United Nations. He was born on June 9, 1924 to Gilbert S. and Margaret Snell Keys in Sierra Madre, CA. He attended Pasadena City College from 1939-1942 and he graduated from the University of Southern California in 1950 after serving in the Air Force during the Second World War. He married Betty Jane Pedersen on August 29, 1950 and they had two children. Keys spent his early career working as a communications technician before becoming involved with the World Federalist Movement, which advocated for the application of solidarity and democracy to world institutions. He served as the executive director of the National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy from 1958-1967 and the executive director of the International League for Human Rights from 1968-69. He then became the representative to the United Nations for the World Association of World Federalists, a position he would hold until 1982. Keys is also known for establishing and directing the group Planetary Citizens, which advocated for cooperation and fellowship among people of all national origins. Keys died on April 10, 2008.
Scope and Content Note
The first series is divided into two subseries: Individuals and Organizations; and Diplomatic Correspondence. Correspondents include: Judith Aitken, Siméon Ake, Peter Archer, Roger Archer, Foster Bailey, Joseph Biden, Jr., Hans Blix, George W. Blount, James F. Cairns, Andrew Clark, Christine Colt, Catherine Costa, Norman Cousins, Eric Cox, Alan Cranston, David Exley, Solomon Faddju, Richard Falk, John Faust, William Feeney, Robert Fleisher, Jack Malcolm Forbes, June Y. Gundersen, Morton Halperin, Fritz Heim, Ed Helm, Margaret Huntington, Alex Hyde, Mike Jeung, Shinichi Kato, Reginald S.H. Kazanjian, Ann Hallan Lakhdhir, York Langton, Rev. Norman Z. Leach, Karin Leonhardt, John Logue, Everett L. Millard, John G. Oakley, Glenn Olds, Daniel G. Partan, Elizabeth Perkins, Reynaldo Galindo Pohl, Victor Rice, Indar Jit Rikhye, Alfonso García Robles, Curtis Roosevelt, Florence Schott, Bill Sheehan, Charles B. Smith, Jr., Sally Thatcher, Philip Tory, Renee Wadlow, Christopher Wagner, Lucy Webster, Donald Wilson, Harry Wiseman.
The WAWF Projects' series includes materials from Donald Keys' time with the WAWF. It is divided into three subseries: Reports and Accompanying Records; Meetings and Conferences; and Speaking Engagements. The last series, Other Organizations, includes meeting minutes, resolutions, correspondence and memoranda of the Ad Hoc Committee on Human Rights and Genocide Treaties, World Congress of Peace Forces, World Federal Authority Committee, and additional groups with which Keys was involved.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. World Association of World Federalists' (WAWF) Projects; III. Other Organizations.
Peace movements; Keys, Donald.; World Association of World Federalists.; United Nations; World Federal Authority Committee.
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  Arrangement
  The first subseries, Individuals and Organizations, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, and occasionally includes carbon copies of correspondence and/or responses from Donald Keys. Some related materials may also be present, such as photographs or printed materials. The second subseries, Diplomatic Correspondence, is arranged chronologically.
  - Individuals and Organizations (Box 1)
    - VIIth Japan Congress of Religionists for Promoting Peace for World Federations., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Acchione, Maria., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Aitken, Judith., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Akashi, Yasushi., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Ake, Siméon., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Al-Khudhairy, Hisham., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Alem, Fehmi., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Jon., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Alger, Chadwick., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Allmand, Warren., 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Amerasighe, H.S., 1973 (Box 1)
    - American Bar Association Arms Control Committee., 1977 (Box 1)
    - American Friends Service Committee., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Americans for SALT., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Amnesty International., 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - Andon, Nancy., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Archer, Peter., 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Archer, Roger W., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Arellano, Thomas L., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Armstrong, Arthur., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Association for Humanist Psychology., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Association of World Colleges and Universities., 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - Association of World Federalists., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Association of World Federalists, Calcutta., 1971-1973 (Box 1)
    - Baha'i International Community., 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Bailey, Foster., 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - Bakay van Dapperen, Thea., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Adelaide N., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Baker, E.G. Stanley., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Baker, Robert., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Bank Mendes Gans nv., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Barnaby, Frank., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Baum, A., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Bebb, Charles., 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - Benfield, K. Michael., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Bennett, Kenneth A., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Berdahl, Clarence A., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Beumer, J. W., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Biden, Joseph R., Jr., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Bilbert, Albert S., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Blanchard, Karen J., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Blanco, Humberto., 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Bliss, L. Denton., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Blix, Hans., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Bloomfield, Lincoln., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Blount, George W., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Blue, Howard., 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - Boaten, Frank E., 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Bodine, Walt., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Boettiger, Beatrice Coddinton., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Boettiger, Edward G., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Booth, Arthur., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Borch, Otto R., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Bray, Sally., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Brinson, Walter J., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Brittain, Roger Dean., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Brown University. (Box 1)
    - Bucci, Victor., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Buffum, William B., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Burton, John., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Butler, William., 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Cairns, James F., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Campaign for UN Reform., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Cape Cod Community College., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Caritas Internationalis., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace., 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Carroll, (Mrs.) John W., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Carter, William., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Cataldo, Michael., Undated (Box 1)
    - CBS Evening News., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Center for War/Peace Studies., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Center for the Study of Power and Peace., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Center for UN Reform Education., 1980 (Box 1)
    - Center of Concern., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Chacko, M. E., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Charles F. Kettering Foundation., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Charravarty, Amiya., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Choo, Edna Coffin., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Chopra, Usha., 1971-1974 (Box 1)
    - Christian Church (Disciples of Christ)., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Citizen Participation in World Affairs., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Clain, F. (Box 1)
    - Clark, Andrew., 1971-1974 (Box 1)
    - Clark, Joseph., 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - Clark, Joseph S., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Cleveland, Ray L., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Close, Philip C., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Coalition on National Priorities and Military Policy., 1970-1972 (Box 1)
    - Coe, George G., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Coker College., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Colman, Ronald L., 1978 (Box 1)
    - Colt, Christine., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Commission Internationale de Juristes., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace., 1973-1977 (Box 1)
    - Committee for the Future., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Communitarian Village., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Community Concern Forum., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Condon, Bernard F., Jr., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Conference of UN Representatives., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Conference for Nuclear Free Pacific., 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Congress of the United States House of Representatives., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Consulate General of the Philippines., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Convention Internationale., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Costa, Catherine M., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Cousins, Norman., 1970-1979 (Box 1)
    - Cox, Eric., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Cranston, Alan., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Crona, Betty Mae., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Damen, Susan Roelofsen., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Dana, Betsy., 1974-1978 (Box 1)
    - Danelius, Neila., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Danhaus, Bertha., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Danilson, Thelma M., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Davidowitz, Moshe., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Davidson, Madelyn., 1972 (Box 1)
    - de Reitman, Sara., 1972-1977 (Box 1)
    - de Rozas, Carlos Ortiz., 1974 (Box 1)
    - de Seynes, Phillipe., 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Deibler, Nancy Wesselman., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Delprée-Crespo, Juan Carlos., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Demeter, John Dewey., 1974 (Box 1)
    - DePaul University., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Deswarte, W., 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - Diocese of California World Without War Program., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Docter, Thomas R., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Drew University., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Duca, George I., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Dunham, Amelia K., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Duhaney, Mrs. Blondeen., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Dunford, Mary L., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Education for Peace., 1973 (Box 1)
    - En Verden., 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Engle, Mrs. Parke F. (Louise)., 1977 (Box 1)
    - English Speaking Union of Pakistan., 1978 (Box 1)
    - ERIC Clearinghouse on Educational Media and Technology., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Ettinger, David., 1973-1976 (Box 1)
    - Everingham, Doug., 1973-1978 (Box 1)
    - Exley, David J., 1971 (Box 1)
    - Faddju, Solomon., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Falk, Richard., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Faust, John R., 1973 (Box 1)
    - The Federalist Caucus., 1979-1981 (Box 1)
    - Les Fedéralists Mondiaux., 1971-1977 (Box 1)
    - Feeney, William R., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Ferencz, Benjamin B., 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Ferguson, Laura., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Fischer, William F., Jr., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Fleisher, Robert., 1972 (Box 1)
    - FN-forbundet Danish United Nations Association., 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Forbes, Jack Malcolm., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Forgy, Larry., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Foster, Mary., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Frank, (Ms.) Ruth., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Frankel, Mortimer., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Franklin Book Programs, Inc., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Frederick, Jane., 1976 (Box 1)
    - French, Gary., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Friends International Centre., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Friends World College., 1973 (Box 1)
    - Gaddes, D. Boyce., 1975 (Box 1)
    - Gage, Barnard., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Gargas, Jr., W. Lawrence., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Gastaut, Thérèse., 1973 (Box 1)
    - George, Robley E., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Ghorayeb, Beshara., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Gilbert, Alfred S., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Gilbert, Don., 1981 (Box 1)
    - Gildemeister, Joan., 1976-1977 (Box 1)
    - Giubardo, Martin., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Glassboro State College Law/Justice Studies., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Glassman, Debra., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Glossop, Ronald J., 1973-1982 (Box 1)
    - Goodman, John., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Goyette, Donald R., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Grant, G. G., 1971-1980 (Box 1)
    - Gray, Herman A., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Greenwood Press., 1979 (Box 1)
    - Greyhound Lines East., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Grönning, Jacob., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Gros, Louis., 1976 (Box 1)
    - Grossman, Jerome., 1977 (Box 1)
    - Grossman, Richard L., 1974 (Box 1)
    - Gundersen, June Y., 1972 (Box 1)
    - Habicht, Max., 1978 (Box 2)
    - Halperin, Morton H., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Hanover College Field Study at the United Nations., 1977 (Box 2)
    - Harris, Mrs. Peter (Sylvia)., 1977 (Box 2)
    - Harry, Ralph L., 1978 (Box 2)
    - Hart, Richard., Undated (Box 2)
    - Heim, Fritz., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Heisler, Stanley D., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Heller, Janet., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Heller, Ruth., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Helm, Ed., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Henderson, Jane., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Hertz Rent a Car., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Hiatt, Thomas., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Hill, Aaron J., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Hinachi, Yasuharu., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Hinerfeld, Ruth J., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Hiroshima, Japan (City of)., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Hitaka, Prof. K., 1975-1978 (Box 2)
    - Hoffman, Walter., 1978 (Box 2)
    - Hollins, Harry B., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Horton, David F., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Howe, Claire., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Huber, Helen., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Huntington, Margaret., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Hurley, John., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Huston, Donald., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Hyde, Alex., 1974-1978 (Box 2)
    - I.C.S.A. Peace Universal Centre., 1974 (Box 2)
    - IDOC / North America., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Igwe, Emenike., Undated (Box 2)
    - Iijima, Soichi., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Industries Atomiques & Spatiales., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Ingvarsson, Ingvi S., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Institute d'études du développement., 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - The Institute for Strategic Studies., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Interlake High School., 1976 (Box 2)
    - The International Committee to Defend Shrii Shrii Anandamurti., 1973 (Box 2)
    - International Cooperation Council., 1976 (Box 2)
    - International Directory for Youth Internships., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - The International Institute for Strategic Studies., 1972 (Box 2)
    - International Peace Academy., 1973-1976 (Box 2)
    - International Peace Petition., 1981 (Box 2)
    - International University of the World., 1973 (Box 2)
    - The International Year Book and Statesmen's Who's Who., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Institute for World Order., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Institute for World Order-, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Jack, Homer A., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Jaipal, Rikhi., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Jeung, Mike., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Job, Cvijeto., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Jonah, James. O.C., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Jong, Youl Yoo., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Joyce, Mary., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kasemsri, Birabhongse., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Kato, Shinichi., 1974-1978 (Box 2)
    - Katz, Milton., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Katz, Zev., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kazanjian, Reginald S.H., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Kelly, James P., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Kenner, Joseph., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kenyon, Jack., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kim, Roy U.T., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Kim, Samuel S., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Kister, Pierre., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Knight, Kenneth., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Kocik, Dennis E., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Koh, T.T.B., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Korey, William., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Kronisch, Myron W., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kumar, Sudarshan., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Kurtz, Howard., 1979 (Box 2)
    - Lafleur, Nicole., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Lakhdhir, Ann Hallan., 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Langlois, Francis., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Langsam, G., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Langton, York., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Laszlo, Ervin., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Laursen, Finn., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Layer, Frances E., 1977 (Box 2)
    - Leach, Rev. Norman Z., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Lee, Kenneth A., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Leonhardt, Karin., 1972-1977 (Box 2)
    - Lewis, A. Barton., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Library of Congress., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Linch, W.D. (Chip)., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Linderman, Nicholas., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Linsenberg, Arlin., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Linzer, Estelle., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Lloyd, William B., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Logue, John., 1973-1978 (Box 2)
    - Londa, Abram D., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Lowe, Constance., 1977 (Box 2)
    - Mac Bride, Sean., 1974 (Box 2)
    - MacGilvra, Ralph A., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Main, John W., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Mankind Center., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Marco Polo Expedition., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Marion, Kevin Michael., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Marsh, Leonard., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Maynes, Charles W., 1976 (Box 2)
    - McClure, (Mrs.) P.D., 1973 (Box 2)
    - McDaniel, Shelley., 1974 (Box 2)
    - McGrath, John Byram., 1976 (Box 2)
    - McVitty, Ed and Marion., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Members of Congress for Peace through Law., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Mendelsohn, John., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Mikelson, Jeanne., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Millard, Everett L., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Mills, Donald Owen., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous., 1972-1981 (Box 2)
    - Mision de Mexico ante Las Naciones Unidas., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Miyake, Rev. Toshio., 1972-1977 (Box 2)
    - Miyasaka, Kojiro., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Mondschein, Jeffrey M., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Moore, Frances Adams., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Morgan, Dr. Russell H., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Morita, Ichi., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Morse, Bradford., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Muller, Gert., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Nachman, Betsy., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Nandan, S.N., 1973 (Box 2)
    - National Wildlife Federation., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Netzorg, Gordon W. (Skip)., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Nevas, Leo., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Nevers, Robert Allison., 1975 (Box 2)
    - New York Times., 1972-1975 (Box 2)
    - Nicholson, Jack B., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Nielson, Knud., 1971-1978 (Box 2)
    - Noel-Baker, Philip., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Nyary, Nicholas., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Oakley, John G., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Olds, Glenn A., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Omniversal Symposium., 1973 (Box 2)
    - One World Trust., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Oresek, Janine., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Osborn, Earl., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Osier, Donald V., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Oster, Barry A., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Pacem in Maribus., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Pakistan Association of World Federalists., 1972-1978 (Box 2)
    - Pakistan Mission to the United Nations., 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - Park, Samuel., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Parliamentarians for World Order., 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Partan, Daniel G., 1973-1976 (Box 2)
    - Pazhwak, Abdur Rahman., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Peabody, Mary E., 1978 (Box 2)
    - Pei, Mildred., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Penney, Freeland F.E.T., 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Peoples for the United Nations World Council., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Perkins, Elizabeth (Beth)., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Perlman, Harold L., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Perry, Charles L., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Petrk, Jaksa., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Phifer, Kenneth W., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Pistrich, Lucy S., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Planetary Citizens., 1972-1982 (Box 2)
    - Plastino, Brookes., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Pohl, Reynaldo Galindo., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Posin, Dan Q., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Postgraduate Center for Mental Health., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Postmaster General., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Powell, William C., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Price, Teresa., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Professional Institute of Public Services of Canada., 1976 (Box 2)
    - Puri, J. N., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Raber, Sam., 1973-1978 (Box 2)
    - Rae, Saul F., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Rakov, Lisa., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Ramphal, Shridath S., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Redd, James M., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Redick, John R., 1973-1977 (Box 2)
    - Refior, Everett L., 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Registre International des Citoyens du Monde Centre International., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Regnell, Hans., 1971 (Box 2)
    - Rehfeld, R. Rex., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Reyes, Narciso G., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Rice, Victor., 1972-1979 (Box 2)
    - Richard Einfeld Productions., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Rikhye, Indar Jit., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Ritchie, Bruce., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Roberts, Thomas., 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Robles, Alfonso García., 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Rokotuivuna, Amelia., 1975 (Box 2)
    - Romula, Carlos P., 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - Roosevelt, Curtis., 1971-1973 (Box 2)
    - Rosenthall, Carla., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Rossides, Zenon., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Rothermel, Timothy S., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Rutgers University. The Political Science Forum., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Rydbeck, Olof., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Saito, Shizuo., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Sakamoto, Yurie., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Samsom, Peter H., 1974 (Box 3)
    - SANE., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Sauvant, Karl P., 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Scali, John., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Schaubacher, Daniel., 1977 (Box 3)
    - Scheerder, Frans., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Schiffman, Joann., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Schleifer, Ervin., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Schlesinger, Joel., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Schneider, Dorothy., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Schoettle, Enid C. B., 1973 (Box 3)
    - School for Esoteric Studies., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Schott, Florence., 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - Schwanke, Robert W., 1975 (Box 3)
    - Seignoret, Eustace., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Sen, Samar., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Shafer, Stephen B., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Sharaf, Abdul Hamid., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Sheehan, Bill., 1976-1978 (Box 3)
    - Shillaker, Robert., 1980 (Box 3)
    - Shockley, Tamara A., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Shore, Lloyd G., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Shower, Mike., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Sidenberg, Lois S., 1977 (Box 3)
    - Sieroty, Alan., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Sills, Joe Byrns., 1975 (Box 3)
    - Singer, Eugenia., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Sinha, Pandit Bhek Pati., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Smail, Barry., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Smedley, Frederic C., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Charles B., Jr., 1974-1975 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Jack., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Ross., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Smythe, Tony., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Societá per la Pace e la Giustizia Internazionale., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Soule, Carl., 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Special Committee of International Non-Governmental Organizations on Human Rights. 1973 (Box 3)
    - Special Non-Governmental Committee on Disarmament., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Spiegel, Jennifer., 1976 (Box 3)
    - Springer, Arthur., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Stahl, Louann., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Stanford, Barbara., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Stanley, C. Maxwell., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Stanley Foundation., 1970-1978 (Box 3)
    - Starobin, L., 1976 (Box 3)
    - Starr, Mark., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Starr, Nancy., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Stedman, C. K., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Steer, Margery W., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Stein, Robert., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Stevens, John., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Stewart, Leland., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Stier, Hugh., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Stockholm International Peace Research Institute., 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - Stollnitz, H. S., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Stott, William., 1976 (Box 3)
    - Stritzinger, Jane., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Sullivan, Michael J. III., 1976 (Box 3)
    - Taber, Rahm., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Tabor, Hans R., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Tannen, Erny., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Task Force for the Nuclear Test Ban., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Thant, U., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Thatcher, Sally., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Thomas, Dorothy E., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Thorton, Guy., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Tilson, Dorothy R., 1978 (Box 3)
    - Time Magazine., 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - Toll, Meynard., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Tory, Philip., 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Transnational Perspectives., 1974-1980 (Box 3)
    - UNICEF., 1974 (Box 3)
    - Unitarian Universalist United Nations Office., 1975 (Box 3)
    - United Nations., 1972-1974 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America., 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America Committee on Arms Control, Disarmament and Peacekeeping., 1973 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America Harbor Area Chapter., 1973 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of Greater Boston and the Massachusetts Division., 1974 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America Michigan Division., 1973 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America Northern California Council., 1973 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Association of the United States of America Southern California Council., 1975 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Division of Human Rights., 1976 (Box 3)